Downloaded From MoviesMod.Org
ALL [lN SPANISH]:
♪ The city's called Duke
The state's called New Mexico ♪
♪ Among the gangsters
The gringos'  fame is inflated ♪
♪ 'Cause of the new drug
They created ♪
♪ They say the color is blue
And the quality pure ♪
♪ This potent drug' s runnin'
Through the city ♪
♪ And no one could stop it
If they wanted to ♪
♪ The cartel's runnin' hot because
They weren't getting respect ♪
♪ Talkin'  'bout some "Heisenberg"
Who owns the market now ♪
♪ No one knows the man since
They' ve never seen his face ♪
♪ The cartel's 'bout respect
And they ain't forgiving ♪
♪ But that homey's dead
He just doesn't know it yet ♪
♪ Heisenberg's fame has got
Down to Michoacan ♪
♪ From way far away
They want to taste that meth ♪
♪ That blue stuff
Has crossed the border ♪
♪ Now New Mexico' s
Livin'  up to its name ♪
♪ Looks just like Mexico
In all the drugs it' s hiding ♪
♪ Except there's a gringo boss
And he's known as "Heisenberg" ♪
♪ The cartel's runnin' hot because
They weren't getting respect ♪
♪ Talkin'  'bout some "Heisenberg"
Who owns the market now ♪
♪ No one knows the man since
They' ve never seen his face ♪
♪ The fury of the cartel
Ain' t no one escaped it yet ♪
♪ But that homey's dead ♪
♪ He just doesn't know it yet ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
WALT:
Nitrogen bonds to oxygen,
which in turn...
You do know
what a bond is?
Um...
A strong force
of attraction.
Covalent bonds,
ionic bonds.
The coming together
of atoms and molecules
to form compounds.
No?
Chemical bonds are what
make matter matter.
Bonds are what hold
the physical world together.
What hold us together.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I got it.
Bonds.
Your test score says otherwise.
It tells me you don't get it at all.
Yeah, but, l mean, 58.
I was close.
[COUGHlNG]
What is "close"?
There's no "close" in science, Barry.
There are right answers
and wrong answers.
"Close" didn't put men on the moon.
Yeah, but l'm just saying,
Mr. White, two points?
Look, if I don't pass chemistry,
I have to go to summer school.
And, l mean, l really studied.
Like, really, really studied.
Like, all night, hard.
And, l mean, l'm so into chemistry
for, like, the concepts.
I just think I might have,
you know, the attention deficit...
Couldn' t you please
just let this slide?
[GROANS]
Don't bullshit a bullshitter.
The answer is no.
Next time, apply yourself.
[PHONE CHIMES]
[DIALING THEN PHONE RINGlNG]
JESSE [ON RECORDlNG]:
Yo. lf l know you, leave a message.
[ANSWERlNG MACHINE BEEPS]
Are you ducking me, or what?
This makes the third time.
Look, l will be leaving this phone on
for another 1 5 minutes, so call me.
Oh, and by the way,
that thing we talked about,
the, uh...
When I said, "Handle it."
Well, don't. Just let it go.
All right.
Come on.
Jesse, open the door.
I know you're home.
Your car is here.
Come on. Hey.
Can I help you?
Uh, no. Thank you.
Well, l'm the manager,
so can we stop
with the pounding, please?
You' re the manager?
Yes. Yes, you can help me.
Absolutely.
I very much need
to get inside here,
so if you have
a master key...
You have a key, right?
Yeah, l have a key.
Look, the person who lives here,
it' s just very important
for me to see him.
And you knocked, right?
Yeah.
He didn' t answer?
Which means...?
Look, l'm his father, all right?
You' re Mr. Jackson?
Yes. That's me.
Walt Jackson.
And you are...?
Jane.
Jane. Very nice to meet you, Jane.
Now, if you wouldn' t mind...
Mr. Jackson,
I'm happy to let you
use my phone.
Wanna call him?
No.
No. I--
As l said, l would like
if you let me inside here,
so that I can check on
my son's well-being.
You understand?
Look, whatever's going on
between the two of you
is family.
I don't get involved
in family.
Jesse doesn' t want you in,
you' re not getting in.
Period.
Sorry.
Come on in, Dad.
Thanks.
You okay?
Yeah.
"Jesse Jackson"?
Do you even...?
Oh, l see you have
a telephone,
at least.
You know,
that blinking thing
I've been calling you on?
Whatever, man.
Hey, give me my--
Give--
I will break this.
I will break this!
Damned druggie idiot.
Is this what you've been doing
the whole time
I've been trying to
reach you?
No. I've been
taking care of business.
What business?
The business you put me on,
asshole.
What, you already forgot?
This business.
Huh?
Does that jog your memory?
Son of a bitch.
You didn't actually--?
Hey, you said--
You said, "Handle it,"
so, you know,
I handled it.
When I said, "Handle it,"
I meant fear and intimidation.
I meant get your money back.
I certainly never meant--
Oh, didn't mean to kill somebody?
No!
Well, too late, yo,
because dude's dead.
Oh, God.
All right? Way dead.
Oh, and,
hey, hey, hey. Here.
Here's your money.
Yeah, 4660 bucks.
Your half.
Spend it in good health,
you miserable son of a bitch.
I didn't say I killed him.
Tell me what happened.
Dude' s wife crushed his head
with an ATM machine.
Crushed his--?
Crushed his head
with an ATM machine
right in front of me.
I mean, crushed it like...
Oh, my God,
the sound,
it' s still in my ears.
You know, and the blood,
like, everywhere.
Like, there was so much,
you would not believe.
Man, will you just
please give me--?
Just give me my weed,
all right?
It helps with my nausea.
So...
you did not kill anyone?
Does anybody think
that you killed anybody?
I called the cops.
You called the cops?
Yeah. You know, l called,
and l split, you know?
And then they came in
and busted her.
God, she was--
She was so zapped
out of her mind.
You know? lt's...
She did it for, like, nothing.
I mean, he told her
she was a skank, but, yo,
I mean, she was a skank.
Can this person identify you?
Can she identify you being there?
She couldn' t identify
her left ass cheek.
She was so zonked.
And she had this...
God, she had this kid.
Listen, l'm a little fuzzy
on the mechanics here,
but could you not stop
this woman from
killing this man?
Look,
she had a gun on me,
all right?
Yeah, my gun, okay? Mine.
Go ahead, say it. Say it.
No, I ain' t no Tuco
or Krazy-8.
I can't run a crew.
Come on. Come on.
Point made, man.
Point made. Yes.
[PHONE RINGING]
JESSE [ON RECORDlNG]:
Yo. lf l know you, leave a message.
[ANSWERlNG MACHINE BEEPS]
BADGER [OVER MACHINE]:
Hey, it's Badger, man.
MAN: What are you doing?
BADGER: Huh?
MAN:
Don't use your real name.
BADGER:
What? That isn't my real name.
Uh, okay.
Yo, we got those pants you wanted.
Thirty-two large, right?
We got them just for you, jefe.
Let' s do some business, yo.
So are you gonna
get back up on that horse?
No.
You get on. All right?
I just want to forget.
I just...
Sorry.
[PEOPLE SPEAKING lN SPANlSH]
Hey.
Hey, what's up with that?
Jesus Malverde,
patron saint of
Mexican drug dealers.
HANK:
Well, yeah, hell,
I know who it is, okay?
Scumbags kneeling down
praying to him:
[IN SPANlSH ACCENT]
"Eh, please, Señor Saint.
Eh, no DEA, please."
[HANK CHUCKLING]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I'm just-- l'm just saying,
why' s he on your desk?
Going after neo-Nazis,
you don't wear swastikas,
right?
Sun Tzu.
Son who?
Sixth-century Chinese general.
Wrote The Art of War.
"If you know your enemy
as yourself,
you' ll fight without danger
in many battles."
Right on.
MAN: Agent Schrader.
Sir.
Glad to have you onboard.
Thanks. Thanks.
Everybody getting you settled in?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Great group of guys.
And gals. And gals.
Guys-- Guys and gals.
That's good.
You couldn' t have picked
a better time to arrive.
We' re about to put a big dent
in the cartel. Right, Vanco?
Yes, sir.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[AGENT SPEAKING lN SPANISH]
[VANCO & AGENTS LAUGHlNG]
[LAUGHING]
[FEDERAL CIVIL DEFENSE
ADMINlSTRATION'S
"DUCK AND COVER" PLAYS]
PETE:
Yo, bro, check it out.
It's a satellite picture of you farting.
"Fat Man and Little Boy."
Sounds like you two.
I got your fat man
in my pants, bitch.
Hey, watch it.
PETE:
It ain' t real, dumb-ass.
Just watch it, is all.
You watch it.
I'm Heisenberg.
You' re Heisenberg?
Yeah, l remember you.
You were the cook.
Let's get this over with.
Where's Jesse?
Busy.
Hey, that's cool.
COMBO:
Real cool.
Totally cool.
PETE:
Hey, uh, hey--
It's all there, man. Every dollar.
Case you wanna, like, count it.
Here?
I'm just saying, uh...
Just saying,
like, we cool, yo.
We ain't got
no confusions
and interpretations
as to who we work for.
And that' s church, yo.
For real.
What have you heard?
Did Jesse really, uh...?
I mean, uh, did he really...
squash that dude's head
with an ATM machine?
PETE:
Word.
Who's saying that?
Damn, man, it' s all over town.
Everybody' s like, "Whoa, snap."
Usually I gotta
chase dudes down
for their money,
but today
everybody's paying up.
True that. Serious.
BADGER:
But, like...
He really did it?
You didn't hear that from me.
[AIR RAID SIREN WAILING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[EXPLOSlON OVER SPEAKERS]
Big lunch.
Oh. Thank you.
Here you go.
WOMAN: Very good, Ms. White.
We' ll consider
your application
and let you know.
SKYLER:
Thank you.
I'd just like to mention
that I have worked here
before.
Really?
When are you due?
Oh.
Several months.
Congratulations.
I see.
Accounting Department.
You left us four years ago?
Family.
We' ll definitely let you know.
Thank you for coming by.
Um, actually,
may I see Ted Beneke?
I-- l think he'll remember me.
Mr. Beneke's very busy today,
unfortunately.
You know, if it's okay,
I'll just--
Just...
Ma'am--
Skyler.
Oh, my God, look at you.
Hey, Ted.
Come in, come in.
Okay.
TED:
No calls, Margaret, thanks.
Come on,
sit down right here.
Okay. Thank you.
You look great.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Heh-heh.
Boy or girl?
Or are you two
keeping it a secret?
Oh, it's a little girl.
We' re very excited.
I'll bet. One of each.
How's Walt Jr.?
Oh, tenth grade,
and he's just growing
like a weed.
He's-- He' s taller
than I am now.
Wow.
Yeah.
I'm betting 6'3", 6'4"
by the time he's finished.
And, wow, handsome.
Oh, my God.
Good genes.
[TED CHUCKLES]
Speaking of movie stars,
those can't be the twins.
TED:
Oh, yeah. Yep. That' s them.
They' re gorgeous.
Yes, they are.
And they know it.
Heh-heh-heh.
I'm in real trouble there,
huh?
Yeah.
So the big office, huh?
Weird, isn't it?
I still think of it
as my dad's.
I miss him.
Me too.
I'd like to think
he'd be proud.
Ahem.
Last year was
our best year yet.
Yeah, he'd be proud.
Walt? How's he doing?
Oh, he's-- He is doing great.
Yeah. He's plugging away.
Great. He's still teaching?
Yeah.
You tell him I said hello.
I will definitely do that.
Um...
To be honest, Ted,
I didn't just stop by to say hello.
I, um...
I was applying
for the data-entry job.
You' re kidding.
Skyler, you were, like,
our go-to bookkeeper.
Yeah. Well...
the economy, you know, so...
Well, you, data-entry?
That'd be a mistake.
Oh.
How about, uh...
get your old job back?
We' re expanding,
and, uh, well,
between you and me,
the whole department's
pretty much of a mess.
Your work would be
cut out for you,
but we could use your help.
Wow.
Okay.
WALT:
All right. Now, this is our territory,
right? Currently.
Hey. Hello.
JESSE:
Yeah, man. Current.
Whatever.
Now, look at this.
Here, here, here
and here.
What does that
look like to you?
Hm?
Opportunities. Golden ones.
That's what that looks like.
No, look.
Look, it's an entire city
full of buyers.
Now, why aren't we
exploiting that?
Because it' s not our territory?
Because we lack initiative.
Initiative.
Yes.
You need to employ
more dealers.
Double, triple your crew.
Those three I met?
They should each have
three, six, nine sub-dealers
working for them.
Exponential growth,
that's the key here.
It's not our territory, man.
Yo, you follow me here, huh?
We go rolling into
these neighborhoods,
other crews
ain't gonna take kindly,
you understand?
Sure, they won' t like it,
but I say they're not gonna
do a thing about it.
Oh. No.
No. Listen, Jesse--
Jesse.
The game has changed.
The word is out that
you are a killer.
What are you talking about?
Apparently, it's all over town.
Somebody crossed you,
you got angry,
you crushed their skull
with an ATM machine.
That's not how it happened.
Who cares,
just as long as it's our
competitors who believe it
and not the police?
Oh, my--
No, don't you see
how great this is?
Look, you-- You are a...
Jesse, look at me.
You are a blowfish.
What?
A blowfish. Think about it.
Small in stature,
not swift, not cunning.
Easy prey for predators,
but the blowfish
has a secret weapon,
doesn't he?
Doesn't he?
What does the blowfish do, Jesse?
What does the blowfish do?
I don't even know--
The blowfish puffs up. Okay?
The blowfish puffs himself up
four, five times larger than normal.
And why?
Why does he do that?
So that it makes him intimidating,
that's why.
Intimidating.
So that the other scarier fish
are scared off.
And that' s you.
You are a blowfish.
You see,
it' s just all an illusion.
Yes, it is.
It's nothing but air.
Now...
who messes with the blowfish,
Jesse?
Nobody.
You' re damn right.
I'm a blowfish.
You are a blowfish.
Say it again.
I'm a blowfish.
Say it like you mean it.
You' re a blowfish. That's right.
Yeah!
Blowfishing this up.
[COUGHlNG]
[TOlLET FLUSHES]
[MAN SPEAKlNG IN SPANlSH]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Hello?
The SkyMall.
Give me the SkyMall,
would you? Pfft.
Vanco,
new guy don't speak Spanish.
What's up?
Hey, white boy,
better learn Español, huh?
This ain't Branson, Missouri,
know what l'm talking about?
You know what? l'll teach you.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
It means,
"Let's make a deal."
VANCO:
So go ahead.
We' re waiting.
Okay.
Right here.
"Item SS4G:
Yankee Stadium final season
commemorative baseball
hand-signed by Derek Jeter."
Vanco, write this down.
Oh, man, watch out.
"661 00ZBG:
large size floor runner."
Look at that, huh?
It's a rug you put on the floor,
except for it looks like
a hundred-dollar bill.
Heh-heh-heh.
I love them.
Get me 20 of them.
I'm gonna put them
all over my casa.
VANCO:
We' ll get you three.
No, you give me 1 0.
VANCO: Five.
[TORTUGA SPEAKING
IN SPANISH]
Hey. How about you stop
jerking us off here?
Where's the meet?
When's it going down?
White boy don' t like
let's make a deal, huh?
White boy's gonna kick your ass,
you don't stop wasting his time.
Schrader...
TORTUGA:
Hey, white boy.
My name' s Tortuga.
You know what that means?
Well, if I had to guess,
I'd say that's Spanish
for "asshole."
Tortuga means "turtle."
That's me.
I take my time, but l always win.
Oh, wait. That reminds me.
I seen this earlier. Lookit.
This is awesome, homes.
Right there, look at that.
"The tranquil tortoise
garden sculpture."
Definitely two of those, huh?
Check it out, huh?
Good likeness.
Hank's doing just great
down there.
He's really making inroads.
I'm sure he is.
He's a hero, after all.
So you gonna
go down to El Paso?
Oh, please.
It's Third World enough
around here.
They keep him busy
every second.
He's already got some
big operation going.
Some kind of
hush-hush deal.
He couldn't tell me
a thing about it
except it' s on the other side
of the border.
Wow,
that sounds exciting.
He's being safe, right?
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
He says he' s mostly
riding a desk.
Which,
between you and me,
is just the way I want it.
Speaking of riding desks,
got myself a job today.
You did not.
As big as you are?
Thank you.
You know I just mean...
Where? With who?
Well, someone willing
to work around that,
apparently.
SKYLER:
Beneke.
You did not.
Is Mr. Grabby-Hands still there?
Marie, that was one time
at a Christmas party.
And he was so drunk,
he was practically slurring
his words.
Just what you want in an executive.
And he apologized profusely.
Plus he's married with a family,
so l'm sure he doesn't wanna
get sued for sexual harassment.
It will not happen again.
Is money that tight?
Yeah.
You know we can always help out.
No, Marie.
You know Walt. He would just...
[DOOR OPENS THEN SHUTS]
Speak of the devil.
WALT: Hey. Hi, Marie.
How are you?
What's up?
Nothing much.
How's things with you?
Good. Good.
SKYLER: Hi, honey.
Dinner'll be about an hour and--
Oh, thanks, sweetie.
Everything okay?
WALT: Everything's perfect.
Oh.
[COUGHlNG]
This is Raisin Bran,
not Raisin Bran Crunch.
So? Same thing.
Not the same thing.
I'll tell you what,
why don't you
do the grocery shopping?
And then you can get
whatever you want.
Great.
It's-- It's not that hard, Mom.
It says "crunch" on the box.
You' re pushing it.
Morning.
SKYLER: Morning, Honey.
Hey, Dad.
Hey.
Um, Dad,
notice anything?
Oh.
Is there a funeral today?
A funeral?
Well--
Oh, Christ, do I look that bad?
No, no, no.
Mom got a job.
A job? Why?
Well, do l need to
get out the checkbook
and show you?
No, I...
Do you think it' s a good idea
in your condition?
No, no. The doctor said
I can work practically
up until I go into labor.
And it's just an office job.
I'm just sitting on my butt.
Where?
SKYLER:
Um, Beneke.
I'm back working in the
Accounting Department.
Skyler, what about
the welding fumes?
Isn't that why you had to quit
in the first place?
They' ve gone green
since then.
They have some kind of
green welding or something.
I didn't smell anything
when l was in there.
Didn't Mr. Beneke
pass away?
Yeah.
Who's running things?
Ted. The son.
Oh.
SKYLER:
Anyway, I have got to go.
I don't wanna be late
my first day back.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
SKYLER:
Okay. Whew.
Wish me luck.
WALT JR.:
Good luck.
Bye.
JESSE:
Hey.
You left your cave.
Yeah.
I was--
I'm missing my TV.
Thinking maybe
I'd hit Costco.
You know,
snag a big-ass wide-screen.
So...
Yeah.
What you drawing?
Damn.
That's good.
Make a hell of a tat.
That's the plan.
Really?
I work part-time,
down at ABQ lnk.
Right on.
Yo, you're a
real good drawer.
I used to do
a little of that.
You used to be a drawer too,
huh?
What stopped you?
Uh...
You know, just...
So tell me something.
What kind of tattoo artist
has no tattoos?
That's way too big a commitment.
[VEHlCLE APPROACHING]
[BIKER WHISTLES]
Hey, man.
You' re Pinkman.
You' re the man!
Everybody' s been talking about you.
Yeah.
Right on, man.
Keep it real.
"Pinkman," huh?
Yeah.
I thought your name
was "Jackson."
HANK:
Well, your snitch
is really earning his nickname.
Are we, uh...?
Are we just on
mañana time?
They' ll show.
Yeah?
Why is that?
You got more catalogs
for him to clean out,
huh?
Maybe a little
Sharper Image
or Pottery Barn?
[CHUCKLlNG]
[IN SPANlSH]
What the hell
are they thinking?
Sending us some loudmouth
who doesn't speak the language?
FEDERALE [IN SPANISH]:
Politics, man. Politics.
VANCO: Supposed to
be some hotshot hero.
I say it's a bunch of crap.
FEDERALE: Hero for
Albuquerque, maybe.
Maybe it don't take
much up there.
[CHUCKLlNG]
Hey, something
I need to know about?
[IN ENGLISH]
What? Oh, that? No, man.
We were just, uh,
singing your praises.
[IN ENGLISH]
Glad to have you.
Welcome aboard.
Thanks.
Hey, is that your guy?
Hey,
I think that's your guy.
What the hell
is he doing down there?
[♪♪♪]
[GROANS]
Schrader, where you going?
We need an evidence bag,
right?
A pretty big one.
[AGENTS LAUGHING]
What's the matter, Schrader?
You act like you never saw
a severed human head
on a tortoise before.
[AGENTS LAUGHING AND
CHATTERlNG IN SPANlSH]
Hey, welcome to--
[AGENTS GROANlNG
AND SCREAMING]
[AGENT SPEAKING lN SPANISH]
VANCO:
My leg.
[SCREAMlNG]
MAN [ON RECORDING ON PA]:
--headed by Werner Heisenberg,
were also undertaken
during the war.
JESSE:
The game has changed, yo.
This is our city, all right?
All of it.
The whole damn place.
Our territory.
We' re staking our claim
that we sell when we want,
where we want.
Now, we're gonna be kings,
understand?
Well, l'm gonna be king.
You guys will be princes
or dukes or something.
I wanna be a knight.
JESSE: But first things first.
We gotta get more dealers.
You know,
foot soldiers, right?
Now, they'll be
working for you.
You' re working for me,
and they're working for you.
You follow me?
Layered, like nachos.
Exponential growth.
Now, that' s success
with a capital S.
Straight up,
straight up.
For shizzle.
Frigging awesome.
Well, we' re set.
Our boys are ready.
Gonna be some
mad cheddar, yo.
Cheddar, Mr. White.
Fat stacks,
dead presidents,
cash money.
Gonna own this city.
We' re not charging enough.
What?
You corner the market,
then raise the price.
Simple economics.
[HUMMlNG]
Oh, hey, Ted.
Come on in.
Looks like they got you
all set up.
Yeah. lt's perfect.
I am close enough to the bathroom
that I don't have to waddle too far.
And that' s very nice.
I figured that might be
a deal-breaker.
Heh-heh. Yeah.
Listen, l...
I wanted to thank you
for having me back.
You don't have to thank me.
I need you.
Wow, Ted, it's a little early
for wine, isn't it?
Oh, damn. It's grape juice.
Been making the girls
breakfast in the morning.
Hey, how is Denise doing?
Uh, we split up,
about a year ago.
I'm sorry.
She' s definitely happier now.
I guess I am too, most days.
Together since high school.
Yeah.
I remember that.
Anyway...
I don't know, people change.
Yes.
Anyway, I just wanted
to welcome you.
Welcome you back. And, uh...
I'll see you around
the vending machines.
[LAUGHS]
Okay.
We should have lunch one day.
Like old times.
Sure.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[BACK DOOR CLOSES]
Oh, hey.
Hey, yourself.
So listen. My, uh...
My name is not really
Jesse Jackson.
Hm.
It's Jesse Pinkman.
And that guy you met,
he's, uh...
He's not my dad.
You' re not gonna kick me out,
are you?
Because I actually
really like it here.
I don't make it my business
what you do.
So long as you don't do it here.
So, hey,
I got this kick-ass
new flat-screen.
Wanna see?
It's, uh, got that thing
where the blacks
are, like, you know,
really, really, really black.
And, um, the Dolby
six-point-whatever.
So it'll really rock the house.
But I'll, you know...
I'll keep it way down,
of course.
I don't know what the hell
is taking so long.
Come on, come on.
[LAS CUATES DE SINALOAS'
"NEGRO Y AZUL (THE BALLAD
OF HEISENBERG)" PLAYS]
Downloaded From MoviesMod.Org